Finding Aid for the University of Tennessee President's Papers, 1867-1954 AR.0001
University of Tennessee Libraries, Special Collections
University of Tennessee President's Papers
1867-1954
University of Tennessee Libraries, Special Collections
Morgan, Harcourt A. (Harcourt Alexander)
Humes, Thomas William
Dabney, Charles William
AR.0001
1997
28.5 Linear Feet (19 boxes)
This collection houses official papers created during the presidencies of Thomas W. Humes (1865-1883), Charles W. Dabney (1887-1904), Brown Ayres (1904-1919), Harcourt Morgan (1919-1934) and James D. Hoskins (1934-1946). These materials include correspondence from each of the five presidents, subject files, faculty lists, and materials documenting university activities dating from the end of the Civil War to the end of World War II.
Conditions Governing Access
Collections are stored offsite, and a minimum of 24 hours is needed to retrieve these items for use. Researchers interested in consulting any of the collections are advised to contact Special Collections.
Acquisition Note
This collection encompasses materials from taken from the office of the president during the presidencies of Thomas W. Humes (1865-1883), Charles W. Dabney (1887-1904), Brown Ayres (1904-1919), Harcourt Morgan (1919-1934), and James D. Hoskins (1934-1946).
Biographical/Historical Note
Following the hiatus in University operations caused by the Civil War, the University of Tennessee's trustees named Thomas William Humes (1815-1892) president in July 1865. It was not until a year later, however, that the institution could resume operations. Humes was a Knoxville native and had graduated from East Tennessee College in 1830 at the age of 15. During Humes's administration, great strides were taken to reorganize and rehabilitate the war-torn campus, including the erection of several new buildings, the addition of new faculty, the addition of medical and dental departments (then located in Nashville), the establishment of an agricultural experiment station, and the state Legislature's 1879 redesignation of the institution as the University of Tennessee. Enrollment also increased, reaching a high of 315 in 1874. In spite of these advances, much of Humes's time in office was occupied by bitter contention between those who would shift the University's curricular emphasis to the agricultural and mechanical arts and those who would retain the traditional academic framework of classics and humanities. Humes stood with the traditionalists, and this stance led to his downfall. The trustees asked for his resignation, and on August 24, 1883, Humes complied.
Humes was not replaced immediately, and the Chairman of the Faculty led the University from 1883 to 1887. The Trustees finally appointed Charles William Dabney (1855-1945) President in 1887. He was the first President to hold a PhD and did much to make the century-old institution on the Hill a university in fact as well as in name. He built a research institution with new laboratories, dormitories, a gymnasium, a library, and further developed the College of Agriculture. He re-organized the faculty and in 1893 women were officially admitted to the University. The Summer School of the South was also implemented during his tenure.
Brown Ayres (1856-1919) replaced Dabney in 1904 and continued to expand the University. During his fifteen year administration Ayres created the colleges of Law, Medicine, and Dentistry, oversaw the building of the Carnegie Library (1911), raised entrance requirements, obtained the University's first appropriation from the state legislature, reorganized the Board of Trustees to include gubernatorial-appointed members from the entire state, provided scholarships based on electoral districts, moved the Medical and Dental colleges to Memphis, and enlarged the Agricultural College to meet the needs of rural families in all parts of Tennessee.
Ayres died suddenly in 1919 and was replaced by Harcourt Alexander Morgan (1867-1950), an agricultural expert and Dean of the Agricultural College. As president, Morgan emphasized UT's role in statewide affairs, arguing that the entire state is its campus, with farms, factories, schools, and homes included in the University's services and responsibilities. With the help of the state legislature, Morgan managed to secure significant funds for new buildings on the Knoxville campus, including an engineering building, two women's dormitories, and Shields-Watkins field. Morgan's political savvy and concern for the financial fortunes of the University led him to exercise caution with respect to those issues which he publicly supported or opposed. In 1925 the Tennessee legislature passed a bill forbidding the teaching of evolution in public schools. Many people believed that because of his statewide popularity, UT's president could have influenced the debate and prevented the act from becoming law. Morgan feared, however, that a public stance one way or the other would jeopardize legislative funding for the University, and declined to take a public stand. In a similar matter Morgan declined to intervene in the dismissal of seven UT faculty members, despite his own reservations about the propriety of the actions, because he did not want to come into open conflict with the deans who had recommended the action. Morgan left in 1933 to take a position as one of three board members on Franklin D. Roosevelt's Tennessee Valley Authority.
Morgan's successor was James Dickason Hoskins (1879-1960), a professor of history and economics, dean of the University, and acting president on two separate occasions. As dean and president, he witnessed an explosion of new physical facilities, including Ayres Hall (1921), Sophronia Strong dormitory (1925), the Home Economics Building (1926), Dabney Hall (1928-1929), the Physics and Geology Building (1928), Ferris Hall (1930), the Library (1931), Henson Hall (1931), the Alumni Memorial Gym (1934), the Hesler Biology Building (1935), and Melrose Hall (1946). During his presidency, Hoskins reiterated a suggestion first made by President Harcourt Morgan in 1922 that a regular faculty retirement plan be instituted, and in 1941 the plan was finally implemented. Under Hoskins's leadership, the University weathered the Great Depression and World War II. By the end of that conflict, Hoskins was seventy-six years old, and in June 1946, he finally retired. He retained an office on the campus, continued to be visible, and worked on a history of the University. In 1950, the library that had been built while he was dean was named after him.
Scope and Contents Note
This collection houses official papers created during the presidencies of Thomas W. Humes (1865-1883), Charles W. Dabney (1887-1904), Brown Ayres (1904-1919), Harcourt Morgan (1919-1934) and James D. Hoskins (1934-1946). These materials include correspondence from each of the five presidents, subject files, faculty lists, and materials documenting university activities dating from the end of the Civil War to the end of World War II. Specific topics covered include the agricultural concerns, annual University budgets, the evolution controversy, World War II campaigns, the Board of Trustees, and the changing student life at the University. Although the University had no President from 1883 to 1887, University activities that took place during this time are documented in this collection.
Interested researchers may also wish to consult AR.0257: Chairman of the Faculty Papers, AR.0144 Presidents Thomas Humes and Charles Dabney Papers, AR.0004: Presidents Charles Dabney, Brown Ayres, Harcourt Morgan, and James Hoskins Papers, 1900-1946, AR.0005: Presidential Papers, 1919-1957, AR.0138 President James Hoskins Papers, 1897-1954, AR.0091 Board of Trustees Records, 1808-1982, AR.0089: Board of Trustees, 1920-1960, AR.0081: Treasurer's Reports, 1905-1928, and AR.0364 Treasurer's Account Books, 1858-1934 for more information about the University of Tennessee during this period in its history.
Arrangement
Collection consists of nineteen boxes.
College presidents -- Tennessee.; University of Tennessee (System). Office of the President; University of Tennessee (System); University of Tennessee, Knoxville
- Advertising, 1882-1887; 127280 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Agricultural College, 1893-1950; 127279 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Agricultural College, Experiment Station, 1884-1950; 127278 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Agricultural College, Budget Reports, 1872-1888; 127277 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Agricultural College, Balance Sheets, 1871 June 17-1880 July 1; 127276 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Agricultural College, Vouchers, 1880 January-1880 July; 127275 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Agricultural College, Vouchers, 1866-1872; 127274 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Agricultural College, Vouchers, 1882-1883; 127273 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Agricultural College, Disbursements, 1869 August -1879 June; 127272 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Agricultural College, Agriculture Hall of Fame, undated; 127271 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Allen, Charles M. Construction Company, Contract Proposals, 1932-1939; 127270 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Allen, Charles M. Construction Company, Lyon Metal Accounts, 1935-1940; 127269 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- East Tennessee Farmers Convention, 1923 May; 394969 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Alumni Association, Administrative Papers, 1893-1952; 127268; (1 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Alumni Association, Administrative Papers, 1893-1952; 127267; (2 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Alumni Association, Personal Papers, 1893-1952; 127266 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Alumni Association, Biographical forms, A-B, 1890-1900; 127265 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Alumni Association, Biographical forms, C, 1890-1900; 127264 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Alumni Association, Biographical forms, D-F, 1890-1900; 127263 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Alumni Association, Biographical forms, G-J, 1890-1900; 127262 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Alumni Association, Biographical forms, K-L, 1890-1900; 127261 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Alumni Association, Biographical forms, M, 1890-1900; 127260 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Alumni Association, Biographical forms, N-O, 1890-1900; 127259 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Alumni Association, Biographical forms, P-R, 1890-1900; 127258 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Alumni Association, Biographical forms, S, 1890-1900; 127257 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Alumni Association, Biographical forms, T-Z, 1890-1900; 127256 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Appropriations (including Million Dollar Appropriations, 1917), 1903-1933; 127255 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Atheist Club, 1927; 127254 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Athletic Association, 1900-1945; 127253 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Ayres, Brown, 1904-1919; 127252 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Black Students, Recommendations, 1881-1912; 127251 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Budget and Finances, The University of Tennessee Schedule for Classification of Expenditures, undated; 127250 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Budget and Finances, Balance Sheets, 1885 March 1-September 30; 127249 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Budget and Finances, Annual Budgets, 1903-1909; 127248 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Budget and Finances, Annual Budgets, 1909-1910, 1913-1914; 127247 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Budget and Finances, Annual Budgets, 1914-1917; 127246 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Budget and Finances, Annual Budgets, 1917-1919; 127245 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Budget and Finances, Annual Budgets, 1919-1920; 127244 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Budget and Finances, Annual Budgets, 1923-1924; 127243 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Budget and Finances, Annual Budgets, 1927-1928; 127242 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Budget and Finances, Annual Budgets, 1929-1930; 127241 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Budget and Finances, Annual Budgets, 1931-1932; 127240 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Budget and Finances, Annual Budgets, 1932-1933; 127239 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Budget and Finances, Department Budget Requests, 1921-1922; 127238 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Budget and Finances, Department Budget Requests, 1924-1925; 127237 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Budget and Finances, Department Budget Requests, A-L, 1925-1926; 127236 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Budget and Finances, Department Budget Requests, M-Z, 1925-1926; 127235 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Budget and Finances, Department Budget Requests, A-G, 1926-1927; 127234 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Budget and Finances, Department Budget Requests, H-Z, 1926-1927; 127233 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Budget and Finances, Department Budget Requests, 1927-1928; 127232 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Budget and Finances, Financial Statement with Auditor's Certificates, 1951 June 30; 127231 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Budget and Finances, Audit Reports, 1935-1936; 127230 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Budget and Finances, Notes, 1867-1880; 127229 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Buildings, 1901-1954; 127228 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Business Administration College, 1903-1950; 127227 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Civil Works Administration, 1933-1935; 127226; (1 of 3) (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Civil Works Administration, 1933-1935; 127225; (2 of 3) (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Civil Works Administration, 1933-1935; 127224; (3 of 3) (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Claxton, Philander P., 1932-1949; 127223 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Corn Borer, 1927; 127222 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Corn Borer, 1928; 127221 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Corn Borer, Related Publications, undated; 127220 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Curriculum, 1911-1915; 127219 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Dabney, Charles W., Other Documents, 1887-1899; 127218 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Dabney, Charles W., Correspondence, A-C, 1887-1904; 127217 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Dabney, Charles W., Correspondence, D-H, 1887-1904; 127216 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Dabney, Charles W., Correspondence, I-R, 1887-1904; 127215 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Dabney, Charles W., Correspondence, S-Z, 1887-1904; 127214 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Dabney, Charles W., Correspondence, A-D, 1901-1902 April; 127213 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Dabney, Charles W., Correspondence, E-M, 1901-1902 April; 127212 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Dabney, Charles W., Correspondence, N-Z, 1901-1902 April; 127211 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Dabney, Charles W., Correspondence, A 1902, July-December; 127210 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Dabney, Charles W., Correspondence, B-Z, 1902 July-December; 127209 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Dabney, Charles W., Correspondence, A-G, 1901-1902; 127208 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Dabney, Charles W., Correspondence, G-Z, 1901-1902; 127207 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Dabney, Charles W., Correspondence, 1901 June-1902 December; 127206; (1 of 4) (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Dabney, Charles W., Correspondence, 1901 June-1902 December; 127205; (2 of 4) (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Dabney, Charles W., Correspondence, 1901 June-1902 December; 127204; (3 of 4) (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Dabney, Charles W., Correspondence, 1901 June-1902 December; 127203; (4 of 4) (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Dabney, Charles W., Correspondence, 1901 November-1902 March; 127202 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Dabney, Charles W., Correspondence, 1903-1904; 127201 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Dabney, Charles W., Correspondence, 1920-1950; 127200 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Dental College, 1911-1950; 127199 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- East Tennessee Farmer's Convention (photograph), 1923 May; 127198 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Education, College of, 1903-1935; 127197 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Engineering College, Correspondence, 1904-1951; 127196 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Engineering College, Experiment Station, 1918-1924; 127195 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- English Department, Applications, 1926; 127194 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- English Department, General Correspondence, 1926; 127193; (1 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 15)
- English Department, General Correspondence, 1926; 127192; (2 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Evolution Controversy, Evidence, undated; 127191 (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Evolution Controversy, Editorials, undated; 127190 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Evolution Controversy, Correspondence, 1923; 127189 (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Evolution Controversy, Correspondence, Neal, John R., 1923; 127188 (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Evolution Controversy, Correspondence, E. Smith, Bolton, 1923; 127187 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Evolution Controversy, F. Schaeffer, George B., 1923; 127186 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Evolution Controversy, Other Correspondence, 1923; 127185 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Evolution Controversy, Other Correspondence, 1923; 127184 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Evolution Controversy, Other Correspondence, 1923; 127183 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Faculty Members, 1877-1886; 127182 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Faculty Members, 1887-1929; 127181 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Faculty Members, A-F, 1930-1934; 127180 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Faculty Members, G-N, 1930-1934; 127179 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Faculty Members, P-Z, 1930-1934; 127178 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Faculty Members, A-E, 1935-1939; 127177 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Faculty Members, F-N, 1935-1939; 127176 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Faculty Members, O-Z, 1935-1939; 127175 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Faculty Members, 1940-1949; 127174 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Fraternities, Correspondence, 1917-1928; 127173 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Fraternities, Nahheeyayli Board Minutes, 1935-1948; 127172 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Gifts to the University, 1920-1951; 127171 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Governors, Tennessee (Includes Harvey Hannah, Austin Peay, Henry Horton), undated; 127170 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Guns for Our Sons Campaign, Letters, 1942; 127169 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Guns for Our Sons Campaign, Commercial Employees, 1942; 127168; (1 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Guns for Our Sons Campaign, Commercial Employees, 1942; 127167; (2 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Guns for Our Sons Campaign, Farmers, 1942; 127166 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Guns for Our Sons Campaign, Housewives, 1942; 127165 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Guns for Our Sons Campaign, Manufacturing and Mining Employees, 1942; 127164 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Guns for Our Sons Campaign, Merchants, Bankers, Insurance Agents, 1942; 127163 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Guns for Our Sons Campaign, No Occupation given, 1942; 127162 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Guns for Our Sons Campaign, Professional Employees, 1942; 127161 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Guns for Our Sons Campaign, Students, 1942; 127160 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Guns for Our Sons Campaign, Two Names, 1942; 127159 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- History, 1880-1950; 127158; (1 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 12)
- History, 1880-1950; 127157; (2 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Hoskins, James D., Applications for Dean of the University, A-G, undated; 127156 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Hoskins, James D., Applications for Dean of the University, H-Z, undated; 127155 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Hoskins, James D., Correspondence, numbered folders 1-2, 1915-1919; 127154 (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Hoskins, James D., Correspondence, numbered folders 3-6, 1915-1919; 127153 (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Hoskins, James D., Correspondence, numbered folders 7, 1915-1919; 127152 (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Hoskins, James D., Correspondence, numbered folders 8-13, 1915-1919; 127151 (Box 8, Folder 19)
- Hoskins, James D., Correspondence, numbered folders 14-22, 1915-1919; 127150 (Box 8, Folder 20)
- Hoskins, James D., Correspondence, numbered folders 23, 1915-1919; 127149 (Box 8, Folder 21)
- Hoskins, James D., Correspondence, numbered folders 24, 1915-1919; 127148 (Box 8, Folder 22)
- Hoskins, James D., Correspondence, numbered folders 25-26, 28, 1915-1919; 127147 (Box 8, Folder 23)
- Hoskins, James D., Correspondence, numbered folders 29-38, 1915-1919; 127146 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Hoskins, James D., Correspondence, numbered folders 41-42, 44, 1915-1919; 127145 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Hoskins, James D., Correspondence, numbered folders 45-46, 1915-1919; 127144 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Hoskins, James D., Correspondence, numbered folders 48-49, 51, 1915-1919; 127143 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Hoskins, James D., Correspondence, numbered folders 58, 1915-1919; 127142 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Hoskins, James D., Correspondence, numbered folders 59-61, 1915-1919; 127141 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Hoskins, James D., Correspondence, A-C, 1916-1917; 127140 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Hoskins, James D., Correspondence, D-G, 1916-1917; 127139 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Hoskins, James D., Correspondence, H-L, 1916-1917; 127138 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Hoskins, James D., Correspondence, M-R, 1916-1917; 127137 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Hoskins, James D., Correspondence, S-Z, 1916-1917; 127136 (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Hoskins, James D., Correspondence, A, 1922; 127135 (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Hoskins, James D., Correspondence, B-C, 1922; 127134 (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Hoskins, James D., Correspondence, C, 1922; 127133 (Box 9, Folder 14)
- Hoskins, James D., Correspondence, E, 1922; 127132; (1 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 15)
- Hoskins, James D., Correspondence, E, 1922; 127131; (2 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 16)
- Hoskins, James D., Correspondence, F-G, 1922; 127130 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Hoskins, James D., Correspondence, H, 1922; 127129 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Hoskins, James D., Correspondence, I-K, 1922; 127128 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Hoskins, James D., Correspondence, L-M, 1922; 127127 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Hoskins, James D., Correspondence, S, 1922; 127126 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Hoskins, James D., Correspondence, T, 1922; 127125 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Hoskins, James D., Correspondence, Y-Z, 1922; 127124 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Hoskins, James D., Correspondence, 1929-1953; 127123 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Hoskins, James D., Transferred Files, A-C, 1913-1916; 127122 (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Hoskins, James D., Transferred Files, D-G, 1913-1916; 127121 (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Hoskins, James D., Transferred Files, H-K, 1913-1916; 127120 (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Hoskins, James D., Transferred Files, L-M, 1913-1916; 127119 (Box 10, Folder 12)
- Hoskins, James D., Transferred Files, N-R, 1913-1916; 127118 (Box 10, Folder 13)
- Hoskins, James D., Transferred Files, S-Z, 1913-1917; 127117 (Box 10, Folder 14)
- Hoskins, James D., Student Files, A-F, 1919-1920; 127116 (Box 10, Folder 15)
- Hoskins, James D., Student Files, G-O, 1919-1920; 127115 (Box 10, Folder 16)
- Hoskins, James D., Student Files, P-Z, 1919-1920; 127114 (Box 10, Folder 17)
- Hoskins, James D., Student Files, A-G, 1920-1921; 127113 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Hoskins, James D., Student Files, H-Z, 1920-1921; 127112 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Hoskins, James D., Genealogy, 127111 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Hoskins, James D., Poetry and Writings (Includes Dollars and Cents in Education speech), 127110 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Humes, Thomas W., General Correspondence, 127109; (1 of 2) (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Humes, Thomas W., General Correspondence, 127108; (2 of 2) (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Humes, Thomas W., Faculty Applications, 127107 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Humes, Thomas W., Resignations, 127106 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Insurance Policies, 1873-1875; 127105 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Journals/Ledgers, Agricultural College, 127104 (Box 11, Folder 10)
- Journals/Ledgers, Biology Department, 127103 (Box 11, Folder 11)
- Journals/Ledgers, Temple, Oliver Perry Foundation, 127102 (Box 11, Folder 12)
- Journals/Ledgers, 1940; 127101 (Box 11, Folder 13)
- Journals/Ledgers, 1943; 127100; (1 of 4) (Box 11, Folder 14)
- Journals/Ledgers, 1943; 127099; (2 of 4) (Box 11, Folder 15)
- Journals/Ledgers, 1943; 127098; (3 of 4) (Box 11, Folder 16)
- Journals/Ledgers, 1943; 127097; (4 of 4) (Box 11, Folder 17)
- Junior College, circa 1920s; 127096 (Box 11, Folder 18)
- Land Grant College Survey, A-D, 1928; 127095 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Land Grant College Survey, E-J, 1928; 127094 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Land Grant College Survey, K-P, 1928; 127093 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Land Grant College Survey, Q-Z, 1928; 127092 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Romance Languages Department Applications, 1931; 127091 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Romance Languages Department Applications, 1932; 127090 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Classical Languages Department Applications, 1883; 127089 (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Law College, 1903-1944; 127088 (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Legislature, 1878-1933; 127087 (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Liberal Arts New Curriculum, 1934; 127086 (Box 12, Folder 10)
- Medical College, 1909-1941; 127085 (Box 12, Folder 11)
- Mediterranean Fruit Fly Eradication, 127084; (1 of 7) (Box 12, Folder 12)
- Mediterranean Fruit Fly Eradication, 127083; (2 of 7) (Box 12, Folder 13)
- Mediterranean Fruit Fly Eradication, 127082; (3 of 7) (Box 12, Folder 14)
- Mediterranean Fruit Fly Eradication, 127081; (4 of 7) (Box 12, Folder 15)